Privacy Policy

Contents

Introduction

Agreement to this Policy

How Licensor may collect information about you in our role as data controller

What information Licensor may collect about you in our role as data controller

Why Licensor processes your personal information in our role as data controller

How we share your personal information in our role as data controller

Legal bases for processing

How we store and secure information we collect

How long we keep information (retention procedures)

How you can access and control your information

Our policy towards children

Changes to this Policy

Introduction

Licensor and its affiliates (hereinafter referred as “Licensor”) respects your right to privacy and we

understand that, when you visit our website, use our free software products (“Software), you prefer to

control the way you share your personal information (“Personal Data”) and preferences. The terms “we”,

“us” and “our” refers to Licensor. The terms “user”, “you”, and “your” refer to site visitors, customers and

any other users of the site.

Licensor provides this Privacy Policy ("Policy") to inform you of our practices with respect to the collection

and use of your Personal Data.

Licensor complies with the Regulation 2016/679/EU of the European Parliament and of the Council of 27

April 2016 on the protection of natural persons with regard to the processing of personal data and on the

free movement of such data (“GDPR”). Licensor acts as both a data controller and a data processor under

GDPR.

Licensor has implemented the following requirements under the GDPR, including but not limited to:

 A record of our Personal Data processing activities;

 Adequate organizational and technical protection measures;

 Request forms and internal instructions for Privacy by Design \& Default, Data Portability, Data

Subject Rights like the Right to be Forgotten.

We collect information globally and primarily store that information on the servers based in the United

States and Germany. We transfer, process and store your information outside of your country of residence,

to wherever we or our third-party service providers operate for the purpose of providing you the Software.

The Personal Data of individuals from EEA and Switzerland is stored on servers based in Germany and

processed in the United States. Regardless of where your information is stored or processed, we apply the

same protection described in this Policy. Licensor offers European builds of desktop products to individuals

from EEA and Switzerland to store the information we collect from your use of the Software on the servers

in Germany. We also use the model contract clauses approved by European Commission as a means of

ensuring adequate protection when transferring data outside of the EEA and Switzerland. By incorporating

model contract clauses into a contract established between the parties transferring data, personal data can

be protected when transferred outside the EEA to countries which have not been deemed by the European

Commission to adequately protect personal data.

Agreement to this Policy

Please read this Policy carefully to understand our policies and practices regarding your information and

how we will treat it. If you do not agree with our policies and practices, your choice is not to use our

Software. By accessing or using our Software, you agree to this Policy. This Policy may change from time

to time. Your continued use of our Software after we make changes is deemed to be acceptance of those

changes, so please check the Policy periodically for updates.

How Licensor may collect information about you in our role as data

controller

We collect information about you and determine the purposes and means of processing your Personal Data

in our role as data controller when you download the Software from Licensor’s website.

Information we collect automatically when you use the Software

We collect information about you when you use our Software, including browsing our websites and taking

certain actions within the Software.

Your use of the Software: We keep track of certain information about you when you interact with any of

our Software. This information includes the features you use; information about the system configuration,

PowerPoint version you use; time you spent using the Software; the links you click on; the type, size and

filenames of attachments you upload to the Software; frequently used search terms; and how you interact

with others on the Software.

Device and Connection Information: We collect information about your computer, phone, tablet, or

other devices you use to access the Software. This device information includes your connection type and

settings when you install, access, update, or use our Software. We also collect information through your

device about your operating system, browser type, IP address, URLs of referring/exit pages, device

identifiers, and crash data. We use your IP address and/or country preference in order to approximate your

location to provide you with a better Software experience.

Cookies: Licensor uses cookies to provide functionality and to recognize you across the Software and

devices. For more information, please see our Cookie Policy, which includes information on how to control

or opt out of the cookies and other tracking technologies.

Information we receive from other sources

We receive information about you from third-party Software, from our related companies, and from our

business partners.

Licensor Partners: We work with a global network of partners who help us to market and promote our

products, generate leads for us, and resell our Software. Some of these partners provide consulting, training

and other services around our Software. We receive information from these partners, such as contact

information, company name, what Licensor products you have purchased or may be interested in,

evaluation information you have provided, what events you have attended, and what country you are in.

Other Partners: We receive information about you and your activities on and off the Software from third-

party partners, such as advertising and market research partners who provide us with information about

your interest in and engagement with, our Software and online advertisements.

What information Licensor may collect about you in our role as data

controller

Licensor may collect the following information about you:

 Your email address.

Why Licensor processes your personal information in our role as data

controller

Licensor processes your Personal Data for the following purposes:

 Provision of Software;

 Conducting market research, conducting retention and customer satisfaction surveys, conducting

marketing activities (including through email newsletters, social media and onsite/offsite and

online/offline advertisement), conducting sales activities (including analyzing your Personal Data and

your use of Licensor Software for making (personalized) offers and quotes with the aim of entering into

a customer relationship, and/or maintaining, renewing or expanding a customer relationship);

 Investigating and processing suspected violations of acceptable use of Licensor Software;

 Complying with statutory obligations, including (a) provision of data to authorized authorities in the

context of criminal investigations, (b) complying with (applicable) data retention obligations, and (c) the

provision to third parties of Personal Data concerning customers in connection with an infringement of

these third parties’ rights.

How we share your personal information in our role as data controller

Licensor may share Personal Data about you with:

 Partners or agents involved in delivering the Software;

 Law enforcement agencies, regulatory organizations, courts or other public authorities to the extent

required by law;

 A Licensor customer, if you notify Licensor that this customer use of Licensor Software violates the

acceptable use of Licensor Software or applicable law;

 A third party that has claimed that your use of the Licensor Software violates the acceptable use of

Licensor Software or applicable law (to the extent such sharing is required by law);

 In certain situations, Licensor may be required to disclose Personal Data in response to lawful requests

by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

Legal bases for processing

If you are an individual in the European Economic Area (EEA) or Switzerland, we collect and process

information about you only where we have legal bases for doing so under applicable EU laws. The legal

bases depend on the Software you use and how you use them. To process your information as described

above, we rely on the following legal bases:

 Performance of a contract: the use of your information is necessary to provide you the Software If you

order and use our Software, we will use your information to carry out our obligation to complete and

administer that Software under the contract that we have with you;

 Legitimate interests: the processing is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by

us, namely for information security. We also want to provide you with the best suitable content of the

website, to improve and promote our products and Software and the content on our website, and for

administrative, fraud detection and legal purposes;

 Consent: we may rely on your consent to use your Personal Data for specific purposes, for example, for

sending newsletters and for certain direct marketing purposes.

How we store and secure information we collect

Information storage. We use data hosting service providers in the United States and Germany to host

the information we collect, and we use technical measures to secure your data.

Technical and organizational security procedures and data transfers. We observe reasonable

procedures to prevent unauthorized access to, and the misuse of Personal Data. We use appropriate

business systems and procedures to protect and safeguard the Personal Data. We also use security

procedures and technical and physical restrictions for accessing and using the Personal Data on our servers.

Only authorized personnel are permitted to access Personal Data in the course of their work.

How long we keep information (retention procedures)

Licensor will store your personal information as long as necessary to perform the purposes of processing as

stated in this Policy. After such time, we will either delete or anonymize your information or, if this is not

possible (for example, because the information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely

store your information and isolate it from any further use until deletion is possible.

We retain your Personal Data for as long as your Software is active and a reasonable period thereafter in

case you decide to re-activate the Software. We also retain some of your information as necessary to comply

with our legal obligations, to resolve disputes, to enforce our agreements, to support business operations,

and to continue to develop and improve our Software. Where we retain information for Software

improvement and development, we take steps to eliminate information that directly identifies you, and we

only use the information to uncover collective insights about the use of our Software, not to specifically

analyze personal characteristics about you.

Marketing information: If you have elected to receive marketing emails from us, we retain information

about your marketing preferences for a reasonable period of time from the date you last expressed interest

in our Software, such as when you last opened an email from us or ceased using your Licensor site account.

We retain information derived from cookies and other tracking technologies for a reasonable period of time

from the date such information was created.

How you can access and control your information

Subject to some limits, you have certain rights regarding your Personal Data and the processing thereof.

PLEASE NOTE THAT OUR CUSTOMERS CONTROL AND MAINTAIN ACCESS TO THEIR DATA THAT IS STORED

BY LICENSOR, AND WE MAY NOT HAVE ACCESS TO THE DATA MAINTAINED BY OUR CUSTOMERS OR EVEN

TO KNOW WHAT DATA IS BEING MAINTAINED.

You have the right to request a copy of your information, to object to our use of your information (including

for marketing purposes), to request the deletion or restriction of your information, or to request your

information in a structured, electronic format.

Our policy towards children

The Software are not directed to individuals under 16. We do not knowingly collect personal information

from children under 16. If we become aware that a child under 16 has provided us with personal information,

we will take steps to delete such information. If you become aware that a child has provided us with personal

information, please contact our support Software.

Changes to this Policy

We may change this Policy from time to time. We will post any privacy policy changes on this page and, if

the changes are significant, we will provide a more prominent notice by adding a notice on the Software

homepages, login screens, or by sending you an email notification. We will also keep prior versions of this

Policy in an archive for your review. We encourage you to review our privacy policy whenever you use the

Software to stay informed about our information practices and the ways you can help protect your privacy.

If you disagree with any changes to this privacy policy, you will need to stop using the Software and

deactivate it.
